Frédéric Louis Ritter Item Scans and Papers MS096
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Scores, 1688 -- 1862; MS096.001; 15 Volumes; 187 Digital Object(s)
  - Le Droit du Seigneur, 1783; MS096.001.014.00001; Martini (Box 14)
    - Title Page, 1783; MS096.001.014.00001.00001; Martini (Box 14)
      Page from Martini Le Droit du Seigneur. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
    - Page 1, 1783; MS096.001.014.00001.00002; Martini (Box 14)
    - Marche, page 101, 1783; MS096.001.014.00001.00003; Martini (Box 14)
  - Euphrosine, 1790; MS096.001.015.00001; Mehul, Joseph (Box 15)
    - Title page, 1790; MS096.001.015.00001.00001; Mehul, Joseph (Box 15)
      Page from Mehul Euphrosine. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
  - La Vestale, MS096.001.016.00001; Spontini, G (Box 16)
    - Title page, MS096.001.016.00001.00001; Spontini, G (Box 16)
      Page from Spontini La Vestale. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment.
- Texts, 1527 -- 1796; MS096.002; 19 Volumes; 34 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains select scanned pages of music theory books from the Frédéric Louis Ritter collection, Special Collections, Tisch Library, which is not a DCA collection. The music theory books date primarily from the 18th century.
  Items listed in this series reflect only the digitized portions of the music theory books.
  - A Plaine and Easie Introduction to Practical Musicke, 1527; MS096.002.003.00001; Morley, Thomas (Box 3)
    - Plain and Easy Introduction to Practical Music, Preface page 1, 1527; MS096.002.003.00001.00001; Morley, Thomas (Box 3)
      Page image from Morley's Plain and Easy Introduction to Practical Music. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
    - Plain and Easy Introduction to Practical Music, Preface page 2, 1527; MS096.002.003.00001.00002 (Box 3)
    - Plain and Easy Introduction to Practical Music, title page, 1527; MS096.002.003.00001.00003; Morley, Thomas (Box 3)
  - A Treatise of the Naturale Grounds, and Principals of Harmony, 1694; MS096.002.004.00001; Holder, W. (Box 4)
    - Treatise on the Natural Grounds and Principles of Harmony, Introduction, page 1, 1694; MS096.002.004.00001.00001; Holder, W. (Box 4)
      Page image from Holder's Treatise on the Natural Grounds and Principles of Harmony. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
    - Treatise on the Natural Grounds and Principles of Harmony, Introduction, page 2, 1694; MS096.002.004.00001.00002; Holder, W. (Box 4)
      Page image from Holder's Natural Grounds and Principles of Harmony. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
  - Le Institution Harmoniche, 1558; MS096.002.005.00001; Chioggia, Zarlino Da (Box 5)
    - Institutione Harmoniche, title page, 1558; MS096.002.005.00001.00001; Zarlino da Chioggia, Gioseffo (Box 5)
      Page image from Zarlino's Institutione Harmoniche. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
    - Institutione Harmoniche, page 323, 1558; MS096.002.005.00001.00002; Zarlino da Chioggia, Gioseffo (Box 5)
      Page image from Institutione Harmoniche. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
    - Institutione Harmoniche, page 324, 1558; MS096.002.005.00001.00003; Zarlino da Chioggia, Gioseffo (Box 5)
    - Institutione Harmoniche, page 25, 1558; MS096.002.005.00001.00004; Zarlino da Chioggia, Gioseffo (Box 5)
  - Gradus ad Parnassum sive Manuductio as Compositionem Musicae Regularem, 1725; MS096.002.006.00001; Fux, J. Jos. (Box 6)
    - Gradus ad Parnassum sive Manuductio ad compositionem musicae regularem, title page, 1725; MS096.002.006.00001.00001; Fux, J. Jos. (Box 6)
      Page image from Fux' Gradus ad Parnassum sive Manductio ad compositionem musicae regularem. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
    - Gradus ad Parnassum sive Manuductio ad compositionem musicae regularem, frontispiece, 1725; MS096.002.006.00001.00002; Fux, J. Jos. (Box 6)
  - Phrynis Mitilanaeus oder satyrisher Componist, 1696; MS096.002.007.00001; Waldthurn, W. Kaspar v. (Box 7)
    - Satyrischer Componist, title page, 1696; MS096.002.007.00001.00001; Printz, Wolfgang Caspar (Box 7)
      Page image from Printz' Satyrischer Componist. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
    - Satyrischer Componist, frontispiece, 1696; MS096.002.007.00001.00002; Printz, Wolfgang Caspar (Box 7)
  - Orchestre; Anleitung wie ein Galant Homme einen vollen Begriff v. d. Hobeir u. Musik erlangen, etc., 1713; MS096.002.008.00001; Mattheson, J. (Box 8)
    - Das Neu-Oroffnete Orchestre, 1713; MS096.002.008.00001.00001; Mattheson, J. (Box 8)
      Page image from Matheson's Das Neu-Oroffnete Orchestre. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
  - Kleine Generalbass Schule, 1725; MS096.002.009.00001; Mattheson, J. (Box 9)
    - Kleine General-Bass Schule, title page, 1725; MS096.002.009.00001.00001; Mattheson, J. (Box 9)
      Page image from Mattheson's Kleine General-Bass Schule. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
    - Kleine General-Bass Schule, frontispiece, 1725; MS096.002.009.00001.00002; Mattheson, J. (Box 9)
    - Kleine General-Bass Schule, page 136, 1725; MS096.002.009.00001.00003; Mattheson, J. (Box 9)
  - General Bass in drei Accorden, 1756; MS096.002.010.00001; Daube, Johann Friedrich (Box 10)
    - General Bass, title page, 1756; MS096.002.010.00001.00001; Daube, Johann Friedrich (Box 10)
      Page image from Daube's General Bass. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
  - Generation Harmonique ou Traite de Musique, 1737; MS096.002.011.00001; Rameau, Jean Philippe (Box 11)
    - Generation Harmonique, title page, 1737; MS096.002.011.00001.00001; Rameau, Jean Philippe (Box 11)
      Page image from Rameau's Generation Harmonique. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
    - Generation Harmonique, page 169, 1737; MS096.002.011.00001.00002; Rameau, Jean Philippe (Box 11)
  - Handbuch bey dem Generalbass u. d. Composition, 2 vols, 1762; MS096.002.012.00001; Marpurg, Friedrich Wilhelm (Box 12)
    - Handbuch bei dem General-bass, title page, 1762; MS096.002.012.00001.00001; Marpurg, Friedrich Wilhelm (Box 12)
      Page image from Marpurg's Handbuch bei dem General-bass. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
  - Die Kunst des reinen satzes in Musik, 1774; MS096.002.013.00001 (Box 13)
    - Die Kunst des reinen satzes, title page, 1774; MS096.002.013.00001.00001; Kirkenberger, Johann Philip (Box 13)
      Page image from Kirkenberger's Die Kunst des reinen satzes, 1774. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
  - Die Kunst des reinen satzes in Musik, 1779; MS096.002.014.00001; Kirnberger, J (Box 14)
    - Die Kunst des reinen satzes, title page, 1779; MS096.002.014.00001.00001; Kirkenberger, Johann Philip (Box 14)
      Page image from Kirkenberger's Die Kunst des reinen satzes, 1779. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
  - Theoretische Musik, 1757; MS096.002.015.00001; Marpurg, Friedrich Wilhelm (Box 15)
    No Date Available
    - Anfangsgrude der Theoretischen Musik, title page, 1757; MS096.002.015.00001.00001; Marpurg, Friedrich Wilhelm (Box 15)
      Page image from Marpurg's Anfangsgrude der Theoretischen Music. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
    - Anfangsgrude der Theoretischen Musik, page 132, 1757; MS096.002.015.00001.00002; Marpurg, Friedrich Wilhelm (Box 15)
  - The Great Abuse of Musick, in two parts, 1711; MS096.002.016.00001; Bedford, Arthur, M.A. (Box 16)
    - The Great Abuse of Musick, Introduction page 1, 1711; MS096.002.016.00001.00001; Bedford, A. (Box 16)
      Page image from Bedford's The Great Abuse of Musick. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
    - The Great Abuse of Musick, Introduction page 2, 1711; MS096.002.016.00001.00002; Bedford, A. (Box 16)
  - Sketches on the Origin, Progress, and Effects of Music, 1793; MS096.002.017.00001; Eastcott, R. (Box 17)
    - Sketches of the Origin, Progress, and Effects of Music, Preface page 1, 1793; MS096.002.017.00001.00001; Eastcott, R. (Box 17)
      Page image from Eastcott's Sketches of the Origin, Progress, and Effects of Music. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
    - Sketches of the Origin, Progress, and Effects of Music, Preface page 2, 1793; MS096.002.017.00001.00002; Eastcott, R. (Box 17)
  - An Essay on Musical Harmony, According to the Nature of that Science, and the Greatest Musical Authors, 1796; MS096.002.018.00001; Kollman, A. F. C. (Box 18)
  - Elemens de musique theorique et pratique, suivant les principles de M. Rameau, 1772; MS096.002.019.00001; D'Alembert (Box 19)
    - Elemens de musique theorique et pratique, suivant les principles de M. Rameau, title page, 1772; MS096.002.019.00001.00001; D'Alembert (Box 19)
      Page image from D'Alembert, Elements de Musique theorique et pratique, suivant les principles de M. Rameau. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
    - Armide, fold out page 1, 1792; MS096.002.019.00001.00002; D'Alembert (Box 19)
    - Armide, fold out page 2, 1792; MS096.002.019.00001.00003; D'Alembert (Box 19)
  - Petit Prophète de Boehmischbroda, 1774; MS096.002.020.00001 (Box 20)
    - Title page, 1774; MS096.002.020.00001.00001 (Box 20)
      Page image from Petit Prophète de Boehmischbroda. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
  - Theatre de M. Favart Vol. 1, 1743; MS096.002.021.00001 (Box 21)
    - Title page and frontispiece, 1743; MS096.002.021.00001.00001 (Box 21)
      Page image fromTheatre de M. Favart Vol. 1. Berger Family Technology Transfer Endowment
- Ritter primary source and collection documents, 1880 -- 1940; MS096.003; 0.25 Linear Feet
  This series contains original letters, copies of biographical sketches, historical catalogs of the Ritter collection c.a. 1940 (as the collection was already intermixed with the overall Albert Metcalf collection by that time), and an unidentified score fragment (language, composer, date); all items were pulled from the DCA collection documentation file, originally MS014, in June 2011. The historical catalogs contain handwritten notes correcting the publication's errors.
  - Correspondence, MS096.003.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Historical Catalogs, MS096.003.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Biographical, MS096.003.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Score Fragment, MS096.003.001.00004 (Box 1)